Casey Shamey

Malverne, NY 11565 | 724-822-9149 | <u>caseyshamey@gmail.com</u> | caseyshamey.com | linkedin.com/in/caseyshamey/

Professional Summary

Recent Hack Reactor graduate with solid software engineering skills and core programing principles across the full stack. Experienced in developing, testing, and debugging JavaScript and Node.js; creating responsive and dynamic UI/UX in frameworks such as React, building, optimizing, and deploying back end systems with AWS and other technologies. Quick to learn and master new technologies; critically think and solve problems; effectively work in both team and self-directed environments; successful in remote and in-person environments.

Education

Remote Fullstack Software Engineering Immersive | Hack Reactor | May 2019

Doctorate (PhD) | University of Missouri | May 2011

Master of Arts (MA) | University of Missouri | May 2006

Bachelor of Arts (BA) | University of Pittsburgh | May 2004

Skills

FRONTEND:

JavaScript (expert) SQL (intermediate) Vue (beginner)

React (expert) Material-UI (intermediate) Backbone (beginner)

HTML (expert) Redux (intermediate)

CSS (expert) jQuery (expert)

Web Development (expert)

Redux (expert)

BACKEND:

Node.js (expert)

Express (expert)

RESTful API (expert)

MongoDB (intermediate)

mySQL (intermediate)

Knex.js (intermediate)

Mongoose (intermediate)

DEV & DEP:

Git (expert) Webpack (intermediate) Jest (beginner)
Github (expert) AWS EC2 micro services (intermediate) Mocha (beginner)
npm (expert) AWS Elastic Beanstalk (intermediate) Chai (beginner)
Debugging (expert) NGINX(intermediate) Docker (beginner)
New Relic (intermediate) pm2 (beginner)

Projects

MANAGER SAL | FRONTEND ENGINEER | JULY 2019 - PRESENT

- · Improve efficiency and UX utility by updating frontend to Vue framework
- · Respond to customer feedback and ensure customer satisfaction by creating additional tools and functionality including dynamic search capability, interactive calendar tools, and scalable interfaces
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, and BootStrap for stylish and modern front end design to further promote organization and attract future business, and reduce back-end data validation

CHOICE | FULLSTACK ENGINEER | APRIL 2019 - MAY 2019

- Ensure responsive and dynamic story creation features utilizing engineered graph data structure for possible story paths, storing nodes with video and choice options for story customization
- · Built responsive React.js front-end with Material-UI for convenient, fun, and intuitive video creation
- Created reusable components and services to consume REST APIs using component-based architecture provided by React
- Designed and implemented node.js back end with MongoDB database to maximize performance and load speed

FOOTBALLER | BACKEND ENGINEER | FEBRUARY 2019 - MARCH 2019

- Developed and tested SQL and noSQL database schemas to maximize seed speed of 10 million plus records with final PostgreSQL iteration of 4 min 30 sec using piped datastreams in order to make initial transfer and load as short as possible
- Produced scalable deployment in AWS EC2 micro services with proxy server integrating with components designed by other team members to improve efficiency and maximize interaction between all components
- Increased performance of deployed application during stress test to 10k rps with less than 1% error rate and less than 2000ms latency using proxies, caching, cloned instances, and load balancing in AWS to ensure accurate and smooth performance for users

Experience

FRONTEND ENGINEER - REMOTE | MANAGER SAL | JULY 2019 - PRESENT

- Improving frontend UI and creating new tools for live web app as part of a small engineering team as response to customer feedback and in communication with app administrator
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, and BootStrap for stylish and modern front end design to further promote organization and attract future business, and reduce back-end data validation
- · Building custom lightweight and efficient features in order to attain smooth and enjoyable UX
- · Implemented user interface using HTML, CSS, AJAX and JavaScript

DEPARTMENT CHAIR | THE URSULINE SCHOOL | SEPTEMBER 2016 – JUNE 2019

- Managed team of 3 teachers utilizing best teaching practices and latest education technologies to increase size of department by 50%
- · Coordinated closely with international students, parents, administrators, and education companies as head of International Student Program to troubleshoot visa problems, navigate competing cultural

expectations, and maintain flow of communication on all levels to achieve satisfaction and understanding in a competitive environment

Interests

World-class balloon twister and apprentice goldsmith who desperately wants to learn to sail.